should you stream to multiple
destinations at the same time uh this is
a this is a video in the sort of IRL
live streamer category and I'm just
going to answer a question really
quickly about this um I have done multi
streaming I've done up to five different
targets at one point I was streaming to
kick Facebook twitch
YouTube and Twitter all at the same same
time and I paid uh 130 bucks a year 120
130 bucks a year to use restream.io and
I love restream.io I think it's a great
tool um one of the things I like about
restream this is different though 100
this is this is this is IRL toolkit and
we're going to talk about that in a
second it's 130 bucks a
month um so the answer is it depends as
usual um but the reason I only stream to
Twitch right now and this is the main
part of the video the reason I only
stream to Twitch right now is primarily
for one reason twitch doesn't turn my
stream off when proprietary music is
broadcast from my stream whether it be
by accident in a Walmart you know
hearing this music or whether it be on
purpose like thousands of other twitch
DJs who don't save their bods and you
know do a morning show or or or or a
night DJ I mean I list my one of my
favorite streamers is you know 80s dance
party and there's no way that 80s dance
party could could exist if it was
YouTube only because YouTube shuts your
stream down if it detects proprietary
music if it detects anything that's
coming from what it thinks is coming
from another YouTube channel or if it
thinks that it's m proprietary music it
will stop you and I got a copyright
strike for doing that uh I was actually
rewrite I was restreaming uh to YouTube
and to twitch and I forgot to click off
the YouTube thing and I was just doing
my regular DJ thing and boom I got a
strike because they'll the first thing
they do is they turn you off and then
they just cut you out all the all
together um and that's it and you get a
strike and so I I mean the YouTube
content that I have as you're watching
right now is so important to me uh that
you're able to get to these videos and
that these videos can exist forever that
the risk of getting another copyright
strike on YouTube is never worth it to
me to me other people might find it okay
to do that and to risk it but I I don't
I I did notice that if I um am using a
speaker or something and the music is
coming through the speaker like many IRL
streamers do that YouTube is more
permissive with that but it still will
turn it off if it's more than two or 60
seconds so like if you are stopped in a
quiet area and they not talking and it
just hears the music it'll shut you down
and and then you're risking getting a
strike and I I I can cannot risk getting
a strike on YouTube I it it doesn't
really matter what I think with regard
to the whole copyright mess uh I'll save
that for another video someday but I I
personally just don't want to risk it so
I do not do a multistream uh for a long
time I was multistreaming to Facebook
which is very very permissive um the
thing I didn't like about that was that
you know there was the latency of
restream so the real question is do you
care about it going to two different
places right and the
major major reason that I only stream to
Twitch is because twitch Integrations so
we have the engagement that comes from
stickers that comes from blurp that
comes from polling that comes from you
know the the IRL toolkit layered on top
of it um you know the the single source
for chat which is also a huge reason
almost a third reason all by itself is
is phenomenal I I watch IRL streamers um
that I love strle with the decision to
multistream or not and it's funny
because a couple of them have gone and
tried to do it mostly because they're
using IRL toolkit which you know allows
two concurrent uh targets and now
they're managing they're managing their
community over here and their community
over here and they can't see the chat
they have to have there's no client that
can you know that puts the both of the
chat streams together and the YouTube
people can't do anything so if you have
like Integrations like like stickers or
something fun you know or one of those
games like stream avatars you can't do
it and so the YouTube people are like I
want to do that and and YouTube has no
intention I've actually worked with the
internal API for YouTube quite a bit
it's absolutely disastrously bad the the
especially the chat API it's a pulling
API you can't it's not a streaming it
doesn't stream the chat messages it you
have to pull to get the latest messages
it's absolutely horrible and that would
be a reason to use restream as well but
that's the reason that when you're using
a multistream platform like stream that
combines all the stuff that you get a
lot of lag you'll get like a ton of
YouTube video uh of YouTube stream uh uh
chat messages and then you'll get you
know intermixed with like the twitch
ones and then you'll get a whole bunch
more YouTube ones and it's just it's not
real time it's messed up and frankly I
think YouTube is just totally totally
miss the boote on streaming they have
made multiple bad architectural
decisions about how to implement live
streaming the only thing positive I can
say about YouTube as a live streaming
platform is that it has a wider audience
even though the audience tends to be
less uh associated with you you get a
lot more random people in there and so
you're dealing with trolling a lot more
because you get a lot more randos in
there that just want to screw around
with you whereas on Twitch they got to
kind of know about twitch which means
it's more likely that they'll find you
from a YouTube video and then they'll
say hey I found your YouTube video and
now I'm on Twitch and here you are and I
added a Twitch account just for you and
so you kind of filter out out the idiots
and to some degree that's been my
personal experience is there's far more
idiots on YouTube uh than there are on
on Twitch even though twitch is
supposedly a gaming platform right and I
think the reason for that is because
twitch takes a conscientious effort on
the part of the person coming and
finding you because it's a good chance
they don't already have it so that
argument that YouTube gets you more
exposure and everything while it's true
for the videos which I have experienced
making these mini videos it's not true
and it's actually kind of a bad thing
when it comes to creating a community
that you have curated that has people in
it that don't have to be banned
instantly that don't say stupid things
that that you know so I found that the
twitch Community has been extremely uh
good in that regard now unfortunately
there are many professional and uh
Regional um restrictions on using twitch
at work and places like that which is
really
sad I can't control that uh but you know
so consolid everything into twitch is is
nice um twitch is also one of the uh
main platforms that's been at the
Forefront I mean twitch is really the
first main main uh live streaming
service period I mean they're the
original one the the IRL streaming
Community kind of was born on it there
are people who have more views and I
mean the other positive thing about
YouTube is there's more money involved
with YouTube I I've seen I've watched
there's a guy who streams from Japan um
and I've seen people pay for his his
$600 camera in one stream you know they
just seriously they're just like dumping
you know $10 donations on him like over
over 40 minutes and that does just not
happen on Twitch I mean you twitch takes
a bigger cut of the money uh as far as I
know and but you know there are a lot
more interesting and entertaining ways
to support a streamer or through twitch
with subs and and raiding the idea of a
raid the discoverability of that the the
recommendation algorithm that that is in
twitch that will will get put your name
in front of somebody else who's
interested in kind of the same thing
it's all so much better in fact it's so
good that I I just don't even bother
anymore I mean it at one point to multi
stream to two different services on
Twitch until last year it was forbidden
by twitch and if you did it you could
you lose your affiliate in fact the
first year uh I used twitch I wanted I
thought it would be better to have
multiple uh you know allow people from
all over the place to come in and see it
and then I learned really quickly that
it wasn't worth it and I felt really bad
because I gave up my affiliate status
which by the way is you can't just click
on a button hey how are you you can't
just click on a button and say no more
affiliate right uh I had to like write a
letter to Twitch because twitch is so
unused to people saying I don't want
affiliate anymore and I was trying to be
you know ethical and follow this this
stuff and I was about to do multi
streaming you know fast forward three
years they're like yeah you can
multistream that's fine nobody cares you
probably don't want to have it might be
messy for your chat but you know and and
it was no big deal I'm like well thanks
a lot you know I could probably not done
that so and then there's you know things
like kick um I I will never stream to
kick and there's a separate video I'll
do a separate video on Kick but the
short version is uh I kick for no reason
at all uh started bouncing and spamming
all of my community uh members on Kick
and twitch uh they sent something like
70 different notifications and emails to
go along with those notifications
including in my Discord and I will never
use it again I mean if they if they
don't even have Baseline
quality assurance so that when my stream
seriously I was I don't know I think the
bit rate might have been a little bit
higher and so they kept restarting they
kept bouncing my stream on Kick and
every time they did it was spaming there
was nothing in there to detect it was
doing it and it kept sending new
notifications everyone's like yelling at
me like why are you sending me all these
notifications why are you blah blah blah
and I was like I am never using kick
again I mean you despite all the things
about gambling and everything I'm never
ever going back um you know at first I
was kind of in amored by the idea of
having another alternative to Twitch and
and everything the only reason I would
ever consider streaming to kick would be
uh if there was no other possible option
to stream whatsoever and then I would do
that uh and as I said with Facebook it's
Facebook is very Niche and it's the
people on Facebook there's no the people
going to find me are going to be people
that are not the people that necessarily
would want to watch a live stream from
me um so I I I stick with just videos
for there so I the conclusion is I
personally think that that the best way
to do to build a community period is to
have a twitch live stream and to do uh
short form videos as many as you can and
by short form I usually mean under 30
minutes I know that's long right um and
then do those daily I think I think
that's really the the way to go about it
it's the way I've been trying to do it
um I've tried everything else wrong it
seems like I do it all wrong until I get
to the good part I have videos that are
17 hours long that I posted to YouTube
uh because you know people could go to
the different the different places and
go see it but the better thing to do is
to just make a bunch of short videos and
then and then link those all together in
a single website like we do on skill
stack. so that's it that's just my
summary of If you want to get into
streaming and you want to if you're
considering multistreaming how to do it
um I will do another video
about uh what I'm thinking about doing
when I hit the road and how to host uh
how to do IRL streaming period um I'm
going to be doing several videos on that
as well uh so I can give you my flavor
of that people are asking me all the
time how I'm doing it and it's just
going to get there's going to be more
questions there so stay tuned for videos
about that